Aaron Marr

Software Engineer

☑ aaron.marr@icloud.com

- **** +44 7808 668 716
- ★ aaronmarr.co.uk
- github.com/aaronmarr

Profile

Front-End Developer with 8+ years experience building websites and applications. Constantly strives for code quality, performance and maintainability. Proficient in JavaScript (ES6) development and Front-End CSS architectures. Also capable in a number of server-side languages including Python, Ruby and PHP.

Work History

Front-End JavaScript Developer @ Headforwards

March 2019 - Present // Pool, UK (On Site)

- Write modern, performant and robust code for a suite of sites and applications
- Design and develop Front-End software components using Angular.js
- Refactor legacy code, ensuring components are testable and easy to maintain
- Re-write CSS codebase using Tailwind, reducing file sizes by orders of magnitude
- Communicate and collaborate with an agile, multi-disciplinary product team
- Suggest, and implement, a number of quality measures including unit tests

Senior Web Developer @ Colateral

April 2017 - March 2019 // Redruth, UK (Part Remote)

- Develop a large-scale Software-as-a-Service product using React and Redux
- Write well-architected, scalable CSS using Sass and BEM
- Roll-out a unit test suite using Mocha and Enzyme
- \bullet Build services and APIs using Node.js and Django
- Work as part of a small, cross-functional team in a start-up environment

Front-End Developer @ Torchbox

April 2016 - April 2017 // Bristol, UK (Fully Remote)

- Build bespoke Front-Ends for Django and Drupal
- Promote, and lead on, style-guide driven development using PatternLab
- Implement modular Sass architectures using BEM and ITCSS methodologies
- Develop custom JavaScript libraries using ES6 and Babel Starter Kit

Front-End Developer @ Freelance

October 2015 - April 2016 // Redruth, UK (Fully Remote)

- Consult and advise on Front-End Sass and HTML5 template architectures
- Promote component-driven development using a range of Front-End frameworks
- Create custom, white-label Twitter Bootstrap themes
- Rapid prototyping using Ruby on Rails

UX/UI Developer @ Dewsign

July 2015 - October 2015 // Falmouth, UK (On Site)

- Lead on Front-End development for websites built using WordPress
- Develop custom WordPress themes and plugins
- Improve daily development practices including local environments using Vagrant
- Propose and implement code style-guides based on idiomatic HTML and CSS

Skills

Programming Languages

JavaScript (ES6), Python, Ruby, PHP, HTML5, Sass, CSS

Libraries and Frameworks

React, Redux, Vue, Vuex, Angular, Gatsby, Eleventy, Tailwind, Ruby on Rails, Django, Express, Koa, D3, Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, jQuery

Tools and Platforms

Emacs, Git, Docker, Travis, Jenkins, Linode, Heroku, MacOS, Linux, Sketch, InVision

Design

Typography, grids, Design Systems, wireframes, prototypes

Education

Falmouth University

Sept 2013 - Sept 2014

Postgraduate Certificate in Higher Education

Falmouth University

Oct 2007 - June 2010 Bachelor of Arts in Digital Media

University of East Anglia

July 2006 - July 2007 Foundation Degree in Computing

Volunteering

Code Club

2017

Run a Code Club (part of Raspberry Pi Foundation) for 11 to 12 year olds, including sessions on Scratch, Python, and event-driven programming using JavaScript

Work History (continued)

UX/UI Developer @ Headforwards

October 2014 - July 2015 // Pool, UK (On Site)

- Front-End Development using JavaScript (Backbone), HTML5 and Sass
- Design key interface elements, using wireframes and interactive prototypes
- Unit testing using Mocha and Chai

Learning Information Designer @ Falmouth University

July 2012 - September 2014 // Falmouth, UK (Part Remote)

- Front-End development using HTML5, JavaScript (jQuery) and Sass
- UX/UI design, including wireframes, story boards and interactive prototypes
- Responsive web design

Learning Technologist (Intern) @ Falmouth University

September 2011 - July 2012 // Falmouth, UK (Part Remote)

• Web design and development for a range of internal systems and websites

Other Interests

Down time

Music, drumming, Craft Beer, festivals, nature, generative art, family time, walks, Cornwall